learnerator.com 2019-09-03

# Privacy Policy | Albert

**1\. WHAT IS ALBERT?**

Albert helps students learn more effectively through engaging practice and real-time feedback. Educators use Albert to extend their instructional capacity by letting Albert challenge students with questions and providing detailed explanations that students can review at their own pace both in and out of school. Albert serves grades 5 through 12 and covers all core academic areas, including reading, writing, math, science, and social studies.

**2\. FORWARD AND DEFINITIONS**

At Learn By Doing, Inc. (“us,” “we,” or “Albert”), we take the security and privacy of user data extremely seriously. We are committed to complying with the student data privacy laws that apply to your use of the Platform and helping our customers comply with FERPA, COPPA, and other regulatory requirements. Read more below and in our [Terms of Use](https://www.albert.io/terms-of-use).

We use the term “User Information” in this policy to refer to information that personally identifies a user of Albert’s platform and other information we receive or create in the course of a User’s usage of the Platform about a User that is linked to information that personally identifies a User. We use the term “Student Information” to refer to User Information that specifically pertains to Student Users of the Platform.

Capitalized words that are not defined herein have the definitions set forth in our [Terms of Use](https://www.albert.io/terms-of-use).

**3\. DATA WE COLLECT**

When you register for, and use the Platform, you may provide us with three types of User Information:

**Personal Data**   
For the general purposes of authentication and roster management, we collect information that is used to identify individual Users (the “Personal Data”). Personal Data does not include Data that has been aggregated or made anonymous such that it can no longer be reasonably associated with a specific person.

The Personal Data that we collect from Users includes:

  * first and last name,
  * email address,
  * age, and
  * school identification code (optional). 

As a general matter, we do not request nor collect any of the following information from Users:

  * physical address(es)
  * telephone number(s
  * photograph or physical likeness
  * date or place of birth
  * social security number
  * dates of attendance in school
  * grade level
  * grades or test scores
  * disciplinary records
  * medical or health records

We collect Personal Data in different ways. For example, we collect Personal Data when Users register for an Albert account and when a User responds to Albert emails or surveys. We also receive Personal Data from other sources (“Integrated Services”), such as identity verification services, like Google and Clever, contingent on Users granting such Integrated Services to share Personal Data with us.

You have the right to decline to share certain elements of Personal Data that we ask you to provide, but must note that doing so may limit your use of certain features and functionality of the Platform. You may edit account information and submissions at any time by accessing your account through the Platform.

**Device Data**   
Like most web-based services, we (or our service providers) may automatically receive and log information on our server logs from your browser or your device when you use our Platform (“Device Data”). For example, this could include cookies, your web browser type, your IP address, and your device’s operating system, among others. If you use Albert on different devices, we may link the information we collect from those different devices to help us provide a consistent Platform across your different devices.

We take measures to ensure that our cookies do not collect personally identifiable or sensitive information. The aggregate information we collect is analyzed and may be combined with similar aggregate information of other users the Platform. You may set your browser to reject cookies; however, this may affect some functions of the Site.

**Usage Data**   
User interactions with our Platform generate data we refer to as “Usage Data”. Usage Data for Student Users may include, for example, the lessons a student chooses to complete and how they performed on those lessons, when a student starts and stops a lesson, and student responses in the lesson. Usage Data for Educator Users may include their class rosters, the lessons they have created and assigned, and their class preferences. Usage Data will be used for educational purposes only.

**4\. HOW WE USE DATA**

**Personal Data**   
We and our third-party software vendors (“Service Providers”) use Personal Data to: (i) provide the Platform, ii) comply with applicable laws, and (iii) promote our products, systems, and tools. Examples of how we may use Personal Data include:

  * To authenticate a user’s identity;
  * To customize the features that we make available to you;
  * To respond to inquiries, send service notices and provide customer support;
  * To communicate regarding a payment, and provide related customer service;
  * For regulatory purposes and compliance with industry standards;
  * To send communications about new features and products;
  * To determine if a student is under 13 for the purposes of COPPA compliance;
  * We do not use Personal Data for maintenance, testing, or improvement of the Platform

**Device Data**   
We use cookies in order to permit you to remain logged in as a User for the duration of your sessions. We use other Device Data to improve the product, deliver a consistent and enjoyable experience, debug, provide customer support, and for aggregate analysis.

**Usage Data**   
We use Usage Data for reporting purposes to teachers and educational agencies, and to test and improve our product. We also use aggregate Usage Data to develop new products, improve or modify our Platform, conduct aggregate analysis and develop business intelligence that enable us to operate, protect, make informed decisions, and report on the performance of, our business.

**5\. HOW WE SHARE DATA**

We do not disclose, share, rent, or sell any User Information to any third parties for commercial uses, such as targeted advertising. We only disclose or share such Personal Data with bona fide Service Providers for purposes related to or arising out of the ordinary course of creation, development, operation, service, and maintenance of the Platform. Such bona fide Service Providers shall only use such User Information for such purposes and not to sell such User Information under any circumstances.

Service Providers who do help us operate our Platform must adhere to privacy and security obligations in a manner consistent with the Company’s policies and practices. For the purposes of illustration, examples of bona fide Service Providers to us are services facilitating cloud-based hosting, online customer support, log-in monitoring and customer engagement services.

**6\. EDUCATOR ACCESS TO STUDENT DATA**

If you are a student using the Platform in connection with a teacher, school, or district (a “School”), your School administrator(s) and teacher(s) (“Educator Users” and each an “Educator User”) may have the ability to access, monitor, use, or disclose data related to User Usage Data and Personal Data. If you are an Educator User, you agree that you will obtain and maintain all required consents from Student Users and their parents or legal guardians when such Student Users are under the age of 13 or the age of consent in the state in which the Student resides to allow: (i) your access, monitoring, use, and disclosure of this data and our providing you with the ability to do so, and (ii) your student User’s use of the Programs.

If a User enrolls in a “class” created by a teacher, on the Platform, the User grants permission to the teacher to view their Personal Data and Usage Data. Enrollments are done via a unique class join code, a unique class join link, direct email invitation, or an Integrated Service.

If you are a student using the Platform in connection with a School and do not believe you or your parent or guardian has provided a consent for the School or your teach to access, monitor, use, or disclose data related to your Usage Data and Personal Data, please contact us immediately at schools@albert.io.

**7\. SECURITY**

All User Information is securely encrypted within our database, which has daily backups and is protected by SSH (Secure Shell) and a firewall. All actions that involve the digital transmission of User Information are handled by a 256-bit SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) encryption.

**8\. DATA RETENTION**

We retain Student Information to provide the Platform to you and our other users and to provide a useful user experience, and not longer than is necessary to do so. When you update your information, we usually keep a backup copy of the prior version for a reasonable period of time in case you need to need to go back to that version.

Users may deactivate their account at any time by accessing their account through the Platform. Deactivating an account means the following:

  * Users will no longer be able to access their account.
  * No further activity may take place on the deactivated account.
  * Users accounts will no longer be publicly visible in the Platform.
  * All data associated with User accounts will be kept for reporting and compliance reasons.
  * User Information for Student Users up until their deactivation date will continue to be shared with any Educator User(s) and   
School(s) that previously had access to such data
  * A deactivated account can be restored, with all User Information intact, upon request
  * For Student Users who deactivate their account, except for Users (including Minor Users) who make a request for deactivation and de-identification (as discussed below), Albert will retain all of their Student Information for four years after their deactivation date. If no request for re-activation is received during that time, all Student Information will be de-identified and the account will not longer be eligible for restoration.

Following the termination of a license, a School may request that we deactivate and de-identify Student Information and we will do so, unless the School or applicable regulations require the retention of such data, in which case the records shall be de-identified upon the expiration of the retention period. Prior to de-identifying any Student Information, we will first ensure that the School has downloaded backups of the same. This shall apply even in the case when the termination of a license is initiated by the Company.

Minor Users (or their parents and/or guardians) may also request to deactivate and de-identify their accounts for any reason, including infancy, and we will do so. If you are a Minor User and would like to deactivate and de-identify your account for any reason, including infancy, please contact us at minors@albert.io.

In the case of a request for deactivation and de-identification, the following happens:

  * We will obfuscate all of the Personal Data in the relevant Student User accounts. This means that their email, first name, last name, salutation, and username get replaced with a long, meaningless identifier that is randomly assigned. This is a one way change, and we can never recover the identity associated with the account after this step. We will perform this obfuscation in our database, all backups that we maintain, and in any Service Providers that we use to deliver the Platform.
  * We will retain all Usage Data associated with the accounts to improve the Platform. These reasons include, but are not limited to: internal data analytics and prevention of fraud and abuse.
  * This action also deactivates all relevant accounts, preventing them from being used in the future. This also means that these deactivated accounts cannot be restored in the future because of the de-identification process.

In order to request an account reactivation, please contact us at hello@albert.io. To request that Student Information be de-identified, please contact us at schools@albert.io.

Please note that the requested deletion will be as comprehensive as possible but is always subject to issues outside of our control, including applicable regulations and laws, your actions and the actions of third parties. We may also need to retain a copy of certain information for legal compliance purposes, including, without limitation, to avoid identity theft or fraud.

**9\. VIEWING AND CORRECTING INFORMATION**

A parent or guardian may review Student Information in the applicable student’s records by viewing the Student’s Albert.io account. The Platform enables any Educator User to permit parents, legal guardians, and eligible pupils to review personally identifiable information contained in Student Information, and to correct erroneous information, in accordance with procedures established by the School.

To the extent that a User opts to share his or her profile with his or her parent or guardian, such User expressly agrees to such sharing and all related responsibilities and liabilities therewith. Minor Users or Child Users cannot opt of sharing his or her profile with his or her parent or guardian.

We fully comply with the Requirements for Accessible Electronic and Information Technology Design as laid out by the U.S. Department of Education here.

**10\. DATA OWNERSHIP AND CONTROL**

Any and all student data provided to Albert, or to which Albert has been granted access, are and shall remain the sole property of the educational agency that provided or granted access to such records.

**11\. USERS UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE**

In accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”), we require parental consent for students under the age of 13 who wish to use Albert (“Child Users”). Albert does not knowingly permit Child Users to register directly for our Platform without the consent of a Parent (defined below) or Educator User on behalf of a Parent. If Albert learns that Personal Data of a Child User has been collected on our Service without parental consent, then Albert will take appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian (“Parent”) and discover that your child under the age of 13 has an account with our Platform without your consent, please alert us at hello@albert.io.

There are two acceptable ways for Child Users to sign up for the Platform:

**1 - Self registration.** When a Child User registers for our Platform, we request an active class enrollment code, birthdate, username, email, password, and a parent’s email address so that we can email the Child User’s Parent in order to seek consent for the Child to use the Platform. Albert does not ask the Child User for any more information than is necessary to provide the Services to the Child User or to seek parental consent. The Child User will not be able to use the Platform while request for consent from the Parent is pending. If we do not receive Parental consent within 14 days, the Child User’s account will be deactivated, and their Personal Data will be deleted from our systems.

**2 - School registration.** When the Platform is used by a School in the classroom for an educational purpose, we permit the School to create Child User accounts and to provide the requisite consent for Albert to collect User Information of a Child User for this purpose, in lieu of parental consent. Schools may create a Child User account by adding students to the Platform through Google Classroom, Clever, or similar single sign-on service, or through a school integration mechanism, or a School may create logins/passwords for each individual student using tools that we provide. When Schools create accounts in this manner, we do not request additional consent from the Parent, as we require Schools to gather those consents. However, when a School or other individual invites a Child User to join the Platform and connect to a Educator User’s class using a class code, we will request parental consent.

Parents may provide consent for a Child User to use the Platform by responding affirmatively to an email sent by Albert to the Parent’s email address provided by the Child User during account creation. If we do not receive consent from the Parent within fourteen 14) days, the Child User’s account will be deactivated and the Child’s Personal Data is deleted from our systems. Until a Parent provides consent in this manner, the Child User will be unable to meaningfully use the Platform.

Parents may review their child’s personal information on Albert, direct us to delete it, and refuse to allow any further collection or use of their child’s information by Albert by revoking their consent. Parents seeking to revoke their consent, review their child’s information, and request a deletion of their child’s data should contact us at schools@albert.io.

**12\. DATA BREACHES**

Within 48 hours of learning about a data breach, or longer reasonable time as may be required by the legitimate needs of applicable law enforcement or as to take measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore reasonable integrity of its systems, we will notify all Users, teachers, Parents, principals, and district administrators whose information may have been improperly disclosed, via email communication to the email address on file for each User. We will inform any Users who oversee those students (i.e. relevant teachers, Parents, principals, and district administrators) if any Student Information or Child User data is involved. This email notification will describe the nature of the data breach, the date of the breach, the types of information that were subject to the breach, and steps that are being taken to protect their Albert.io accounts going forward.

**13\. NOTICE OF CHANGES**

If we are going to make any changes to this Privacy Policy that would change our practices around what data we collect, how we collect that data, or that would lessen the previously noted protections around student data privacy in a material way, we will notify all users at least 30 calendar days in advance of making such a change. We will provide notification via the emails associated with the profiles of our users.

**14\. CONTACTING US**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

Privacy Director  
Learn By Doing, Inc.  
233 N Michigan Ave, Ste 1440  
Chicago, IL 60611  
hello@albert.io  
(312) 470-2290

**15\. CALIFORNIA AB 1584 COMPLIANCE STATEMENT**

This Statement describes the policies and procedures employed by Learning Genie to ensure compliance with the requirements set forth in Section 49073.1 of the California Education Code (the “Code”).

1\. _Ownership of Student Information._ See Section 10 of this Privacy Policy  
2\. _Student-generated content._ The Platform does not collect or store any student-generated content. In the event the Platform is updated to incorporate such a feature, we will amend this statement to describe the means by which students may retain possession and control of student-generated content  
3\. _Third party access and use._ See Section 5 of this Privacy Policy.  
 _4\. Parent and pupil review procedures._ See Section 9 of this Privacy Policy.  
5\. _Security and confidentiality of Student Information._ Albert.io is committed to maintaining the security and confidentiality of Student Information. It has designated a Security Compliance Officer (SCO), who is responsible for: (a) ensuring that the Company’s servers are protected against unauthorized access to the greatest degree possible; (b) limiting employee access to Student Information to whatever extent is required for them to perform their job functions; and (c) regularly training employees in data security procedures to further ensure compliance with company data security policies.  
6\. _Unauthorized disclosure._ See Section 12 of this Privacy Policy.  
7\. _Post-contract data deletion._ See Section 8 of this Privacy Policy.  
8\. _FERPA compliance._ Albert.io offers schools and districts utilizing the Platform the means to comply with their obligations under the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 USC §1232(g)), by enabling Educator Users to inspect and review Student Information and to correct any inaccuracies therein as described in Section 8 of this Statement.  
9\. _Prohibition against targeted advertising._ See Section 5 of this Privacy Policy.

**16\. INTERNATIONAL PRIVACY PRACTICES**

If you are using the Platform, including the Site out of the United States, your data and information is collected in the country in which you are located and is transferred to the United States or another country where our servers are located.

If you would like to request to review, correct, restrict or delete personal information that you have previously provided to us, object to the processing of personal information, or if you would like to request to receive an electronic copy of your personal information for purposes of transmitting it to another company (to the extent this right to data portability is provided to you by applicable law), please contact us at hello@albert.io. We will respond to your request in accordance with the applicable law that governs the collection, use and deletion of your data and information. The requested deletion will be as comprehensive as possible but is always subject to issues outside of our control, including applicable regulations and laws, your actions and the actions of third parties. It is important to note that we may retain a copy of the information for archival purposes and to avoid identity theft or fraud.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority of your habitual residence, place of work or place of alleged infringement, if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable law. A list of EU data protection authorities is available at: <http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080.>

* * *
